artvan.com 2018-12-09

# Privacy Policy

By sharing the Privacy Policy for Art Van Furniture, LLC (“Art Van”, “we” or “us”), we hope to help you understand how sharing information can create new opportunities for you, our customer, as well as to reassure you that we respect and honor your requests to restrict and protect personal information. Please review this policy carefully.

By using artvan.com or our mobile apps, engaging with us on social media including on our social media sites (collectively referred to as Art Van “websites”), coming to our stores, making a purchase from our catalogs, calling customer service, interacting with us in any way, or utilizing any of our services, you acknowledge your understanding that the practices described in this this Privacy Policy will govern your use of our websites and Art Van’s collection, sharing and use of information you provide to us.

## Information We Collect

Art Van collects two types of information about you: personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information. Non-personally identifiable information is anonymous information that cannot be used to identify you. Personally identifiable information is information that can be used to identify you. The two types of information are used for different purposes. 

When you make a purchase in one of our stores or on our websites, create an account, participate in a sweepstakes or contest or any other promotion, post a product review, engage with us on our various social media platforms, answer one of our surveys, apply for credit with any of Art Van’s 3rd party service providers that provide consumer credit services, pick up purchases at our store or warehouse, or interact with us in any way, you may give us personally identifiable information such as your name, e-mail address, mailing address, zip code, location, phone number(s), financial information (only if you have applied for credit or extended financing) and credit card numbers. We may also ask you to confirm your identity by providing identification or providing personal information to verify your identity. This allows us to provide you with our services, to process your transactions more efficiently, to increase the security of our transactions and ultimately to give you a higher caliber of customer service. We may also use this information, in a way consistent with applicable laws, to provide you with notice of different events and products that we believe might be of interest to you. 

The decision to provide information to, such as described above, is optional. However, if you choose not to provide the requested information, you may not be able to use some or all of the features of our websites or our services. For example, if you don’t provide us with your address we can’t deliver your goods; if you don’t provide us with a cell number we can’t confirm your delivery by text. We may also receive personal information through your use of social media websites and services or from other sources. 

Please note that we will never use your credit card information other than to process payment for your purchase. We do not keep your credit card information on file. When you make a purchase with us, whether on-line or in our store, the credit card information you provide is “tokenized” which means that a service encrypts your data so that it can only be read by the credit card company. Likewise, if you “save” your credit card information with us for future purchases, this information is also tokenized. Even Art Van employees do not have access to your credit card number. 

We will never request that you provide us with your password, user name, or other personally identifiable information over e-mail. An e-mail request for this information is probably a scam and may be an attempt to steal your personal information. If you receive an e-mail from Art Van asking for this information, please do not respond. 

## Usage and Websites Activity Information

When you visit our websites, including on a mobile device, our web server automatically recognizes your internet service provider, domain name, operating system, browser type, the address of the webpage you are coming from, the date and time you access the websites and the pages you requested and visited. This is non-personally identifiable information and generally is not associated with your personal information. Art Van uses this information to statistically measure traffic and flow on the websites, and other traffic statistics such as the percentage of people who visit our site who also make a purchase. We will also use this information to enhance your experience. We also gather customer information by taking note of the purchases you make. By looking at your purchases in context with marketing demographics, it helps our buyers and merchandisers continue to seek out products and designs that might be of interest to you. 

## In Store Information

We use Wi-Fi technology to track location analytics in some of our store locations. This data is used to improve the store layout and enhance the customer shopping experience in our stores. The data collected is non-personally identifiable and works by sensing the presence of smartphones. Certain device information is collected that does not include personally identifiable information unless you have consented to the collection of personally identifiable information. This service is provided to us by our Service Providers. We also use cameras in our stores for the same purposes as well as for security and loss prevention purposes. 

## Social Media

We engage with customers on various social media platforms like Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest and Instagram. If you contact us on one of these platforms for any purpose we may contact you via direct message. Those communications are governed by this policy as well as the policy of the applicable social media platform and any applicable laws and regulations. 

## Access Via a Mobile Device

If you access our websites through your mobile device, we may collect your geo-location. We also collect device type and other unique identifiers. If you enter our stores with a smart mobile device we may also collect information on your browsing and shopping patterns. This information enables us to analyze shopping patterns and to provide you with information that might be of interest to you. 

## Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies

“Cookies” are small amounts of data that are stored on your computer. They find their way to your browser via a Web server. Cookies flag information about your activity on our websites. This information helps us improve our websites and make it friendlier and easier to use and assists us to focus our marketing to areas in which you may have an interest. We never use cookies to save passwords, credit card numbers or other highly confidential information. However, we may use them and other tracking technologies to provide enhanced online marketing based on your interests and preferences. 

To opt out of our cookies used for these personalized online ads, please click here. We will place an “opt-out cookie” on your computer should you opt out of the Service Providers who use cookies. The “opt-out cookie” is browser specific and device specific and only lasts until cookies are cleared from your browser or device. The opt-out cookie will not work for some cookies that are important to how our websites or mobile apps work (“essential cookies”). If the cookie is removed or deleted, if you updated your browser or if you visit us from a different computer, you will need to return to this form to re-select your preferences. If you would like to opt out of accepting cookies all together, you can generally set your browser to not accept cookies or to notify you when you are sent a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. However, certain features of our web site or other services may not work if you delete or disable cookies. 

Web cookies are used in some e-mail messages and on our websites to help us measure the effectiveness of those e-mails and for other analytical purposes. You can “opt out” of this e-mail cookie at any time by deleting your name from our e-mail mailing list(s) by following the procedure described below. 

We also contract with various service providers to help us assess visitation to our websites. To do this, we place small pixel tags (sometimes referred to as “web beacons”) along with cookies on our websites. While these do allow our service providers to track your visits, the data retrieved cannot be used for any reason without our authorization. Although our service provider logs information about your visit, we control how that data may and may not be used. We may track information across the different devices you use to access the websites. 

## How We Use Your Information

The personal information we collect is primarily intended to communicate with you, to offer better customer service, to improve communications and to confirm your identity. We may share your information with independently-owned Art Van Furniture retail stores or our affiliates (people or entities that control Art Van, are controlled by Art Van, or is under common control with Art Van) or are vendors and marketing partners to provide products and services, to fulfill requests, process transactions and provide delivery. We may share your information with third party service providers to fulfill any product service request outside of our service area and to provide certain services including credit card processing, shipping, data analysis and management and promotional services. Customer information from the brands we sell may be combined to provide greater security and used to inform customers of products and services that may interest them. When a purchased item is not immediately available, many of our customers appreciate receiving an e-mail or text to update the status of their order. We may also need to contact customer by phone, postal mail or e-mail or text if questions arise regarding their orders. We also use personal information to send you information about products, services and promotions that we think we be of interest to you. All of these contacts are subject to applicable laws and regulations.

When you shop at one of our stores, order from our catalogs or visit us online, it is also an opportunity for you to provide us with information and feedback on your purchases and service that helps us continue to bring new ideas, unique products, better service and a creative approach to shopping for your home.

## Third Party Service Providers

In order to serve you better, we may at times contract with other companies (“Service Providers”) to help us process information and provide other services to us. For instance, their assistance can help us fulfill customer orders, manage, store and enhance customer data, send marketing, run promotions, and provide other services. For your security, these companies are bound by our nondisclosure agreements or other contractual arrangements to provide privacy protection for your information. 

## Advertising and On-Line Tracking

We contract with Service Providers to place our banner advertising on other websites. These Service Providers may collect information from us about your visits to our websites and stores, and your interaction with our products and services. They may also use this information to tailor banner advertisements for goods and services. This non-personally identifiable information is collected through the use of a pixel tag, which is technology used by major websites. Regardless of anything contrary in this Privacy Policy, personal information may be shared with our Service Providers and their service providers, including, without limitation, your name, postal address and e-mail address, as well as a record of any transactions you conduct on our websites or offline in order to deliver banner advertisements and other advertising tailored to your interests when you visit certain websites. We may track this information across the different devices you use to access the websites. Our contractual terms require our Service Providers to keep this data anonymous and they are prohibited from sharing any personal information with any other third parties, except as required to provide fulfill their obligations to Art Van. 

Our systems do not recognize browser “Do Not Track” signals, but several of our service providers who utilize these cookies and other tracking technologies on our websites enable you to opt out of this type of advertising. To opt out of these ads, please [click here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/). Please also visit the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) or the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) to learn more about the use of information by our Service Providers or to choose limited use of this information by opting out of interest-based on-line advertising. To unsubscribe from marketing emails, open the email and select the unsubscribe button at the bottom. Once redirected to the Preference Center, scroll to the section labeled “How would you like to hear from us?” then select “Unsubscribe me”. This will remove you from all commercial email marketing sends.

## SMS or Text Messaging

If you provide us with your mobile phone number we may use that number to send SMS or text messages regarding the status of an order or for other information and non-marketing purposes.

By texting JOIN to 278826 (ARTVAN) you authorize Art Van to send you text messages with special offers and other marketing messages to the phone number from which you send your JOIN message. You confirm that you understand that you are not required to provide your authorization as a condition of purchasing any property, goods, or services. 4msgs/mo. Reply HELP for help, STOP to cancel. Msg. & Data Rates May Apply.

Compatible carriers include: AT&T, T-Mobile®, Verizon Wireless, Sprint, Boost, U.S. Cellular, Cellular One, MetroPCS, ACS/Alaska, Bluegrass Cellular, Cellular One of East Central Illinois, Centennial Wireless, Cox Communications, EKN/Appalachian Wireless, GCI, Illinois Valley Cellular, Immix/Keystone Wireless, Inland Cellular, Nex-Tech Wireless, Rural Cellular Corporation, Thumb Cellular, United Wireless, West Central (WCC), Cellcom, Cellsouth, Cricket, Cincinnati Bell and Virgin Mobile.

T-Mobile® is not liable for delayed or undelivered messages.

To discontinue receiving SMS messages from Art Van, text STOP to 278826 (ARTVAN).

For additional help, text HELP to 278826 (ARTVAN), email us at [privacy@artvan.com](mailto:privacy@artvan.com) or call [888-427-8826](tel:8884278826).

Only with your express written consent will we send information regarding sales, promotions, or other marketing information via SMS or text. At Art Van, you can “opt in” to receive SMS or text messages in multiple ways: (1) by signing a statement on an invoice or marketing form on which you grant permission to send SMS or text marketing messages to your mobile device; (2) by electronically signing a document on our website granting permission to send SMS or text marketing messages to your mobile device; (3) or by granting permission through text by use of a “double opt-in”. What we mean by a double opt-in is that you will first grant permission for Art Van to contact you via SMS or text for marketing purposes and will then receive a confirmatory text back asking you to confirm that have granted Art Van permission to contact you via SMS or text for marketing purposes. Only after responding “YES” to the text message will Art Van send you notices regarding sales and other promotions by text. Once you have agreed to receive these messages by text, you can stop receiving them at any time by responding with “STOP” to the text message or by contacting Art Van at [privacy@artvan.com](mailto:privacy@artvan.com) and requesting that you no longer receive these messages.

## Information Sharing

Information sharing helps us to guard against potential fraud and other wrongdoing. We review transactions internally on a regular basis to identify potential concerns and we partner with select outside companies to further enhance our ability to ensure that fraudulent orders and/or potentially damaging worms, viruses and other types of malware do not interfere with our ability to provide the best possible products, value and services to you and our other valued customers. 

We may also disclose your information as necessary to comply with legal process (for example, court orders, subpoenas, and warrants) and to comply with laws or regulations. We also may use and disclose your personal information if necessary to protect the safety, property, or other rights of Art Van, our customers, employees, vendors or other persons. 

In the event of a sale or merger of our business, assets or brands, information we have collected as described in this Privacy Policy may be transferred as business assets. 

## Your Information Sharing Choices

We appreciate and respect that not all customers may wish to benefit from the opportunity to share information with other select companies. If you do not want us to share your personal information for marketing purposes, please immediately contact us at [service@artvan.com](mailto:service@artvan.com) and we will remove your name from lists we share with other companies. When contacting us, please clearly state your request, including your name, mailing address, e-mail address and phone number. After we process your request, your personal information will no longer be shared for marketing purposes.

It is important to understand that with some companies or on-line partners, your information must be shared in order to receive their services. For example, when you order a large furniture item, we may send your name, address, e-mail address and phone number to the manufacturer or shipping vendor to arrange for shipment or to enable you to access their on-line delivery scheduling system. The manufacturer or shipping company will not share your personal information with third parties; it is used strictly to coordinate and complete your order or the shipment of your items.

Opting out of sharing your information for marketing purposes will not prevent your relevant information from being provided as needed to fulfill your order, obtain financing or credit approval or for other non-marketing purposes. Similarly, this will not prevent us from sharing your non-personally identified information when it is combined with the data of others (“non-identifiable aggregated data”). 

If you have installed our mobile app, we may send push notifications to your mobile device. You can deactivate these messages at any time by changing the notification settings on your mobile device. 

## Security

Art Van uses industry-standard technology called Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) which encrypts (or encodes) sensitive information before it is sent over the internet and we use reasonable efforts to protect the privacy of your information. This includes payment information. However, due to the inherent risk of using the internet, including viruses and the threat of hackers, Art Van cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you provide to us and you do so at your own risk.

When you make a purchase online, either a solid key or a locked padlock icon will appear in the lower right of your browser window. The icon indicates that your transaction session secured through SSL. If one of these icons does not appear, please contact us at [(888) 427-8826](tel:8884278826) to complete your purchase. 

## Update Your Information

Updating your contact information is quick and easy. Just contact us at [service@artvan.com](mailto:service@artvan.com). Please include your previous and current full name, mail address, e-mail address and phone number or make changes directly through your account. Please understand updates may take some time to process. 

## Protecting Children’s Privacy

Art Van’s services and its websites are not directed at or intended for use by children. We will never intentionally collect information from children under the age of 13 and if we learn that we have, we will promptly delete such information. Please notify us immediately if you have reason to believe that we inadvertently received information from a child under the age of 13. 

## California Privacy Rights

This Privacy Statement generally describes how we share information for marketing and other purposes and it applies to all Art Van customers including those who reside in California. Residents of California with whom we have established a business relationship have the right to request from us certain information with respect to the types of personally identifiable information we have shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes by such third parties and the identifies of the third parties with whom we have shared information during the immediately preceding calendar year. All requests for such information must be in writing and sent to Art Vann Furniture, Advertising Department, 6500 E. 14 Mile Rd., Warren Mi. 48092 or by e-mail to [privacy@artvan.com](mailto:privacy@artvan.com).

California users under the age of 18 may request the removal of their content or information publically posted on the websites by e-mailing us at [privacy@artvan.com](mailto:privacy@artvan.com). 

## Your Responsibilities

You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your account and password and for restricting access to your computer. You are responsible for all activities that occur under your account or password. As a result, it is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a computer used by others. 

## A Privacy Promise

We support and adhere to the guidelines and practices adopted by the Direct Marketing Association’s Privacy Promise and the Digital Advertising Alliance Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. In doing so, we agree to comply with a customer’s requests to not share their information with other companies or to contact them for marketing purposes by postal mail, telephone, e-mail or through on-line behavioral advertising.

If at any time, as a customer, you believe that are not committed to this Privacy Policy please contact us at [privacy@artvan.com](mailto:privacy@artvan.com). You may also contact the DMA’s Committee on Ethical Business Practices. 

## Processing In The United States

Please be aware that your personal information and communications may be transferred to and maintained on servers or databases located outside your state, province or country. If you are located outside the United States, please be advised that we process and store all information in the United States. The laws in the United States may not be as protective of your privacy as those in your location. Bu using our websites or our services, you agree that the collection, use transfer and disclosure of your personal information and communications will be governed by the applicable laws in the United States. 

## Privacy Policy Updates

Efforts to bring new services, ideas and partners to benefit our customers may make it necessary to amend our Privacy Policy. If this occurs, we will post the new policy on our websites. Once posted, the new policy will go into effect immediately, replacing any previously stated policy. Your continued use of our websites or services constitutes your consent to the revised Privacy Policy. 

## Questions or Requests for Additional Information

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, you can contact us at [privacy@artvan.com](mailto:privacy@artvan.com) or you can call our customer service department at [(877) 939-5373](tel:8779395373).
